Your time will come...
The Island is a action, thriller, science fiction film directed by Michael Bay.
In 2019, Lincoln Six-Echo is a resident of a
seemingly "Utopian" but contained facility.
Like all of the inhabitants of this carefully-controlled environment, Lincoln hopes to be chosen
to go to The Island — reportedly the last uncontaminated location on the planet.
But Lincoln soon discovers that everything about his existence is a lie.
Lincoln Six Echo / Tom Lincoln, played by Ewan McGregor.
Jordan Two Delta / Sarah Jordan, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Albert Laurent, played by Djimon Hounsou.
Dr. Bernard Merrick, played by Sean Bean.
James 'Mac' McCord, played by Steve Buscemi.
Starkweather Two Delta / Jamal Starkweather, played by Michael Clarke Duncan.
The Island is a 2005 American science fiction action film directed and co-produced by Michael Bay and
written by Caspian Tredwell-Owen, Alex Kurtzman and Roberto Orci, from a story by Tredwell-Owen.
It stars Ewan McGregor, Scarlett Johansson, Djimon Hounsou, Sean
Bean, Michael Clarke Duncan, and Steve Buscemi.
The film is about two human clones, Lincoln Six Echo (McGregor) and Jordan Two Delta
(Johansson), who live in a utopian compound isolated from the outside world.
After Lincoln learns that the compound inhabitants are clones used for organ harvesting as well as surrogacy
for wealthy people, the two escape with the goal of exposing the illegal cloning movement.
The Island has been described as a pastiche of "escape-from-dystopia" science fiction films of the 1960s
and 1970s, such as Fahrenheit 451, THX 1138, Parts: The Clonus Horror, and Logan's Run.
The Island cost $126 million to produce.
It opened on July 22, 2005, by DreamWorks Pictures in North
America and internationally by Warner Bros.
Pictures, to mixed reviews, earning $36 million at the United States box office
and $127 million overseas for a $162 million worldwide total.
The film explores themes of genetics, love of one's
life, escape, freedom, dystopia.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.